Guide to the Journals,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Davidson Taylor Journals,
1959-1964
Taylor, Davidson, 1907-
15 v. (4 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, N.Y.
4079391
Biographical Note
Scope and Content
Journals and notes kept by Taylor during his directorship of the Arts Center Program at Columbia University. One of the volumes relates to the Rodgers and Hammerstein Theatre proposal.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Journals
Subjects
Columbia University.--Arts Center Program.; Arts--New York (State)--New York.; Theaters--New York (State)--New York.; Diaries.; Rodgers and Hammerstein Theatre.; College administrators.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-5. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1975 M-75 Taylor, Davidson
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Wheelock, John Hall To Davidson and Mary Elizabeth, [Long Island, NY], 25 December 1961, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Wheelock, John Hall Song, Long Island, NY, August 1961, (1 page a.ms.s.) (Box 1)
    [Inscribed on the latter above. Gift, 1989]
  - St. Bartholomew's Church A Memorial Service for Davidson Taylor, New York, 19 September 1979, (2 page Order of Service) (Box 1)
- Series II: Journals
  - Subseries II.1: Journal 1
    - Index of contents followed by "Interviews" with Douglas More; Erik Barnouw; Richard Rodgers; Eric Bentley; Benjamin Buttenwiser; Ben Sonnenberg; and Jacques Barzun, etc., [New York], 19 May - 25 August 1959, (1 volume) (Box 1)
  - Subseries II.2: Journal 2
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Erpf; Barnouw; Collins; Hibbitt; Kimball; Lavan; Moore; Palmer; Schapiro; Schuster; Upjohn; Ussachevsky; Wittkower; etc. [New York], 27 August-27 November 1959, (1 volume) (Box 1)
  - Subseries II.3: Journal 3
    - Index of contents followed by transcripts of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Erpf; Bell; Dietz; Handleman; Keene; Kirstein; Lambert; Matthews; Owens; Phillips; Rodgers; Schapiro; Schnitzer; Trottenberg; Warren; Young, etc., [New York], 2 December 1959-13 May 1960, (1 volume) (Box 1)
  - Subseries II.4: Journal 4
    - "In this volume, the Rodgers and Hammerstein Theatre negotiations begin. This material is separated and kept in [this] small volume. Material about the Theatre in this volume copied f[rom] other one. All entries in small volume appear in this index through the closing date of this volume.", [New York], 12 May-18 November 1960, (1 volume) (Box 2)
  - Subseries II.5: Journal 5
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Krpf; Reisinger; etc., [New York], 16 November 1960 - 12 April 1961, (1 volume) (Box 2)
  - Subseries II.6: Journal 6
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Bentley; Dale; Krim; Lehman; Warburg; etc., [New York], 17 April - 30 October 1961, (1 volume) (Box 2)
  - Subseries II.7: Journal 7
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Astor; Beaumont; Cerf; Kempner; Loos; Mazur; Naumburg; Rodgers and Hammerstein; Rosenwald; Sonnenberg; etc. [New York], 16 October 1961 - 12 March 1962, (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Subseries II.8: Journal 8
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Beaumont; Bentley; Delacorte; Farrell; Haas; Luce; McLeish; Podell; Simon; Vogel; etc., [New York], 13 March - 15 June 1962, (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Subseries II.9: Journal 9
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Beaumont; Bentley; Carman; Hogan; Inness-Brown; Luce; Mielziner; Palmer; Segal; Tyson; Wertheim; Xanthos; etc., [New York], June 18 - 20 November 1962, (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Subseries II.10: Journal 10
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Beeson; Calvert; de Barry; Hammer; Milburn; Papp; Teichmann; Valency; etc., [New York], 26 November - 4 March 1962, (1 volume) (Box 4)
  - Subseries II.11: Journal 11
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Alexander; Bornemann; Dowling; Friedberg; Houghton; Matthews; Moe; Pool; Redman; Salvatore; Teighman; Vogel; Wrightsman; etc, [New York], 3 March - 26 August 1963, (1 volume) (Box 4)
  - Subseries II.12: Journal 12
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Barnouw; Compton; Hale; Leff; Moe; Park; Snow; Truman; Woodbridge, etc., [New York], 3 September 1963 - 30 June 1964, (1 volume) (Box 4)
  - Subseries II.13: Journal 13
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Barzun; Coffee; Hadyn; Koch; Lowry; Park; Raynal; Shanet; Vogel; Warren; Wittower; Xanthos, [New York], 13 July 1964 - 20 October 1965, (1 volume) (Box 5)
  - Subseries II.14: Journal 14
    - Index of contents followed by notes of talks with various professors, administrators, and supporters: Kirk; Barzun; Salmen; Barnouw; Deane; Leary; McCabe; Shanet; Swann; Teichman; Walton, etc., [New York], 1 November 1965 - 24 June 1968, (1 volume) (Box 5)
  - Subseries II.15: Journal [15]
    - Notes on conversations and discussions with various people at Columbia University and outside regarding the Rodgers and Hammerstein Theatre project., [New York], 9 September 1960 - 18 July 1963, (1 volume) (Box 5)